### **Adam Coll**

## **Web Developer**

I've enjoyed working with a broad set of technologies and stacks over the years but I always come back to web development. The open and unrestricted nature combined with the increasing capabilities of the mobile web provides a platform with endless potential. Building real-time or interactive web based experiences that seamlessly bridge desktop and mobile are my favorite kinds of projects.

# **Experience**

#### Mitrend 2013 - Current

Working with the brilliant team at Mitrend for the past 6 years has been tremendously rewarding. I started out implementing data parsing and normalization pipelines in Java before moving on to building interactive reports for the web in Backbone.js. Over the past few years I transitioned into a technical leadership role for the web development team as we converted our web stack to React.js and Typescript.

- Full stack development on a Backbone, Jade, Sass, React, Styled Components, Nodejs, Express, MySQL webapp.
- Java development for data processing.
- DevOps / Infrastructure deployment with AWS resources.

### <u>Symbotic</u> 2012 - 2013

- Full stack development on a jQuery, Java, Struts webapp that communicated with other systems via ActiveMQ.
- Development and architecture experience on a C# Data Access Layer reusable module.

#### C&S Wholesale Grocers 2010 - 2012

- Full stack development on SenchaJS, PHP, MySQL internal resource management applications.
- DevOps / Infrastructure experience with physical to virtual migrations and internal application management.

# **Other Interests**

- Building native feeling web apps using PWA features.
- Custom Elements and Preact
- GraphQL and serverless architecture.
- <u>Firebase</u> for small applications

# **Education**

Keene State College BS, Computer Science